Xander Bakx

Q Boston, Massachusetts
 ∑ xanderbakx@gmail.com
 ☐ (707) 217-8780
 ii in/xander-bakx
 △ xanderbakx.dev

SUMMARY

Software engineer with full-stack experience developing web and mobile applications in small teams. Graduated from Fullstack Academy in October 2020. I am familiar with a range of languages and technologies with a focus on React and Node.

EXPERIENCE

Test Engineer | Hillrom | Acton, MA | May 2019 - May 2020

- · Collaborated on a small team to implement regulatory measures to ensure the continued sales of 20 percent of Hillrom products.
- Performed verification & validation testing on over 200 medical devices to ensure EU MDR compliance.
- Independently developed custom microcontroller-powered system run on C++ code to facilitate life-cycle testing of multiple products.
- Collaborated with the engineering department to determine testing procedures, design changes, product obsolescence, etc.
- · Facilitated the shipment and testing procedures of approximately 100 medical devices for ISTA packaging validation testing.

LMS Coordinator | Clarks | Waltham, MA | July 2018 - May 2019

- · Provided support to users and assisted in resolving issues relating to LMS access and technical functionality.
- · Organized instructor-led training (ILT) schedule and enrollment, eLearning content library, and user group assignments.
- Published, tested, and troubleshoot online custom learning content and oversaw relationships with related content vendors and host providers.

Freelance Web Developer | Self-Employed | July 2017 - July 2020

- Designed, developed, hosted, and maintained responsive websites for small businesses and built static websites with modern technologies including Gatsby, Netlify, React, Styled Components.
- Communicated with clients to improve the design and functionality of current websites and designed logos and edited photos in Adobe Illustrator, Lightroom, and Photoshop.

PROJECTS

Collabio | Side Project | May 2021

- Source code at github.com/xanderbakx/collabiodocs.
- · Developed a full-stack web application for users to collaboratively create and edit rich text documents.
- Built an Express server with Auth0 and Passport.js authentication and authorization.
- Created React components with Redux state management and Slate.js rich text library and designed and implemented Mongo database to store document nodes.

Cook'd | Fullstack Academy | October 2020

- Source code at github.com/Do-Jest-While-True.
- · Developed a React Native application to view and share recipes and built an Express server with user Passport is authentication.
- Designed a PostgreSQL database and implemented REST API routes to fetch data and created React components with Redux state management for likes, comments, and recipe feeds.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Certificate: Full Stack Software Engineer | Fullstack Academy | New York, NY | 2020 Bachelor of Arts (BA): Economics | Management Information Systems | University of Oklahoma | 2016

INVOLVEMENT

Boys & Girls Club of Boston | Tutor | October 2019 - February 2020

• Tutored high school students in weekly 1-on-1 sessions.

University of Oklahoma | Division 1 NCAA Gymnast | 2012 – 2016

• 2015 NCAA National Champions, 2015 MPSF Champions.

SKILLS

Proficient: JavaScript, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, Node.js, Gatsby, Express, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git

Knowledgeable: Babel, Webpack, MongoDB, Heroku, Expo, Netlify

Some Experience: Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Chai, Auth0